The pressure is building...
Dante's Peak is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Roger Donaldson.
Volcanologist Harry Dalton comes to the sleepy town of Dante's Peak to investigate
the recent rumblings of the dormant volcano the burg is named for.
Before long, his worst fears are realized when a massive eruption hits, and immediately, Harry, the mayor
and the townspeople find themselves fighting for their lives amid a catastrophic nightmare.
Harry Dalton, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Rachel Wando, played by Linda Hamilton.
Nancy, played by Arabella Field.
Lauren Wando, played by Jamie Renée Smith.
Graham Wando, played by Jeremy Foley.
Ruth, played by Elizabeth Hoffman.
Dante's Peak is a 1997 American disaster film directed by Roger Donaldson, written by Leslie
Bohem, and starring Pierce Brosnan, Linda Hamilton, and Charles Hallahan.
The film is set in the fictional town of Dante's Peak where the inhabitants fight to survive the
eruption of a long dormant stratovolcano that has suddenly become active again.
The film was released on February 7, 1997, under the production of
Universal Pictures and Pacific Western Productions.
The release came just weeks prior to the similarly themed film, Volcano,
starring Tommy Lee Jones, which came out in April of the same year.
It is the third film collaboration between Gale Anne Hurd and Hamilton, who
both previously worked in the first two Terminator films.
The film explores themes of rescue, small town, helicopter, lava, mayor.
The tone is emotional and intense.